Utkarsh Agrawal

Account and Marketing Manager

Professional Account Manager with more than 6.5 years of experience in Account Management, Campaign Management and Ad-Operations (Programmatic & Non-Programmatic). Involved in the development of new business opportunities, management, product training in ad-tech & food tech industries.

\times	utkarsh.agrawal.395@gmail.com
•	+91-9198480822
9	New Delhi, India
in	linkedin.com/in/utkagrawal
S	live:utkarsh.agrawal_5

SKILLS						
Account Management Real Time B	idding Programm	natic Marketing C	ampaign Managemen	Ad Operations		
Customer Relationship Management	Digital Strategy	Product Training	Problem Solving	Profit Maximizariton		
Time Management Negotiation						

WORK EXPERIENCE

Deputy Manager - Campaign Management Samsung Electronics

06/2022 - Present

Achievements/Tasks

- Partner with the Account Management team through each step of the campaign process i.e from ideation to reporting,
- Assist in RFP responses to ensure ease of setup by ad operations team. Advise on strategic media plans based on campaign objectives and budgets,
- Partner with Ad-Ops to troubleshoot delivery issues and optimization strategies. Work with CSMs and Inventory team to understand inventory and delivery options,
- Review creative and assets to ensure no assets are missing and full compliance of all trackers fired.
- Accounts Handled: HistoryTV, Nickleodeon, MTV, VH1, Tubi, Disney etc.
- Servers Worked On: Adgear, Google DCM, Innovid, Nielsen DAR etc.

Ad Operations Manager Xapads Media

10/2020 - 06/2022

Tasks

- Overseeing and Managing Programmatic and XML Supply Partners portfolio including setup, strategy, troubleshooting and reporting of all the SSPs across all the programmatically running campaigns with the success of new partners.
- Being the RTB, XML, and Header Bidding expert for the Publisher/Account Management Team.
- Supporting Tech and Demand team that will further drive into the betterment of performance along with cost optimization.
- Contribution to New Business workflows (pricing grids, development, and managing account transitions).
- Ad Exchanges worked: UnityAds, AdColony, PropellerAds, Evadav etc.
- Servers Worked on: Adkernel, Appsflyer, Affise, Zedo, PropellerAds, Brandmatic, AppOcean, Trackier, Adcash, Aarth.

Assistant Account Manager MoMAGIC Technologies

03/2019 - 10/2020

Tasks

- Responsible for all new preferred deals and pre-empt partners as well as relationship management of existing deals and clients.
- Work closely with the programmatic yield and operations team to rapidly onboard new customers.
- Build, maintain, and manage relationships with Agencies, Trading Desks, DSPs, networks, and all demand sources.
- Assist in the creation of a cogent sales deck on programmatic media using various parameters i.e. market trends, MoMAGIC products, etc.
- Performance analysis of the campaign to upscale the spend.
- Clients: OpenX, Taboola, Mediamath, IndexExchange, Smaato etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Expert - SAAS Account Manager dineout - Times Internet

06/2017 - 03/2019

Tasks

- Acting in line with targets assigned by company on a monthly level,
- Establishment & Management of inResto SAAS product at the restaurant,
- Coordinating with client in order to ensure that renewal for inResto products happen on time,
- Along with inResto, started working for Torqus POS and its inventory management system (Collectively Acquired by Dineout). The Role consisted of initiation of POS setup, SCM setup, training, client handling and the account management, post the client is on-boarded by Business Development team. (Feb & March'19),
- Clients: Crowne Plaza, Le-Meridien, Holiday-Inn, LOD etc.

EDUCATION

PDGM - Business Management Narsee Monjee Institute of Management Studies 06/2020 - 12/2022

Bachelor Of Technology - IT SRMCEM

08/2013 - 05/2017

ACHIEVEMENTS

Received Best Performer Award by MD at Samsung Eletronics for History Channel Account.

Received SPOT Award by VP at Samsung Electronics while working on Tubi TV Account.

In Xapads, drove the revenue up to 200% of the normal revenue with effective management of SSPs traffic accross all the supply sources.

Within 5 months of working in MoMAGIC, I was promoted to manage Programmatic accounts.

In Dineout, I was promoted as a sub team lead and head of the inresto accounts for central Delhi region.

Represented district in the native language essay competition.

Publishing of patent poetry in a weekly journal.